Tony Schwartz Collection
Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, Library of Congress
- Series 2. Business and Professional Materials, 1940–2005, 54 linear feet
  - Client projects: public service announcements (PSAs), circa 1940s–2002, undated
    - Patrolmen's Benevolent Association of the City of New York, 1981–1994
      - International Radio Festival of New York awards, 1984-07–1994-09-13 (Box-folder 106/6)
        Articles on awards Schwartz received for his Patrolmen's Benevolent Association radio commercials, including "Two Cops" (aka "Two Officers"), 1984.
        See also SmokeFree Educational Services and "Two Cops" photographs (below).
      - Photographs taken from "Two Cops" PBA spot produced by Tony Schwartz, circa 1984 (Box-folder 225/14)
        Two 8x10 inch and four 11x14 inch black and white photographic prints taken from a Tony Schwartz PBA spot that garnered him an International Radio Festival of New York award in 1984. The spot was also known as "Two Officers."
        See also International Radio Festival of New York award file, above.
      - Scripts, 1981–1984 (Box-folder 106/7)
      - Boxing Team jacket, undated (Box 228)
        A purple satin jacket that presumably was given to Tony Schwartz. The front is embroidered "Champions of Cops, Ken McFeeley & Tony Schwartz." The back shows an image of a police badge and the text "The Fighting Finest, City of New York Police, PBA, Boxing Team."
        See also Ken McFeeley files.
    - Peace Corps scripts and research, 1985-09-04–1985-10-14 (Box-folder 106/8)
    - Pennsylvanians for the Right to Choose Life scripts, correspondence, and research, 1981-06-18–1981-07-01 (Box-folder 107/1)
    - People for a Smoke-Free Indoors, 1986–1989
      See also the Group Against Smoking Pollution (GASP).
      - Scripts, correspondence, and interviews, 1987-10-29–1989-10-20 (Box-folder 107/2)
        Includes materials relating to the group's chairman, Dr. William G. Cahan. Scripts include a message for Kansas Senator Robert Dole and Massachusetts Governor Michael Dukakis.
      - Scripts, correspondence, and research materials, 1986-03-04–1988-08-05 (Box-folder 107/3)
        Two anti-smoking buttons are included.
      - Color photographs of People for a Smoke-Free Indoors members at Tony Schwartz's home studio, circa 1986 (Box 202)
        Six 4x6 inch color photographs of group members meeting in Tony Schwartz's home studio.
      - Scripts and correspondence, 1987-11-18–1988-12 (Box-folder 107/4)
      - Scripts, correspondence, and research materials, 1986-06-03–1988-07-03 (Box-folder 107/5)
        Material on Joe Cherner and New York City Mayor Ed Koch.
      - Correspondence and research materials, 1986-10-16–1987-03-19 (Box-folder 107/6)
      - Scripts, articles, and correspondence relating to Mayor Ed Koch, 1986-03-22–1986-07-02 (Box-folder 107/7)
      - Anti-smoking contest, 1988-01-20–1988-04-22 (Box-folder 107/8)
      - Color photographs of posters exhibited for anti-smoking contest, circa 1988 (Box 202)
        Twenty-three 4x6 inch color photographs of anti-smoking posters.
    - People for the American Way, 1980–1990
      - Scripts and research materials, 1981–1987-09-15 (Box-folder 108/1-2)
        Includes a large packet on the Peace Corps from 1981 celebrating its 20th anniversary.
      - Scripts, correspondence, and research materials, 1986-05-13–1990-06-14 (Box-folder 108/3)
      - Scripts, correspondence, and research materials, 1980-08-22–1980-11-09 (Box-folder 108/4)
    - People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals brochures and correspondence, 1986–1988-05-05 (Box-folder 108/5)
      The organization's acronym is PETA.
    - People of Westpride, Inc. scripts, correspondence, and research materials, 1988-04–1988-05-17 (Box-folder 108/6)
    - Two script drafts for People Who Care about Preserving Williamstown as a Special Place for Living the Good Life, undated (Box-folder 109/1)
      Contact: Hal Zeiger.
    - Philadelphia unions script and report, 1990-11-08–1990-12-17 (Box-folder 109/2)
      Includes material on the Fraternal Order of Police, Lodge 5, and the International Association of Firefighters, Local 22. Also includes an American Federation of TV and Radio Artists HR report.
      See also Fraternal Order of Police, Lodge 5.
    - Phobia Society of America scripts, correspondence, and research materials, 1985-07-16–1986-05-14 (Box-folder 109/3)
    - Physicians for a Smoke Free Canada material, 1987-06-10–1987-11-26, Anti-smoking. (Box-folder 109/4)
    - Physicians for Social Responsibility scripts, correspondence, and research materials, 1983-10-21–1984-04-11 (Box-folder 109/5)
    - Attitudes survey for the Police Foundation of New York City, 1990-11 (Box-folder 109/6)
      A Survey of Attitudes Toward Crime in New York City conducted by Napolitan Associates.
    - Police Superior Officer's Association of Newburgh materials, 1993-10-18 (Box-folder 109/7)
    - Poor Americans for Fair Taxation scripts and research materials, 1985-05-31–1985-11-18 (Box-folder 109/8)
    - Processed Apples Institute script and report, 1989-02-23–1989-03-08 (Box-folder 109/9)
    - Proposition 2 1/2 scripts and correspondence, 1980-10-01–1980-11-04 (Box-folder 109/10)
    - Prudential Insurance Company of America, 1986–1990
      - Scripts, correspondence, research, survey, and contracts, 1986-02-18–1990-10-30 (Box-folder 109/11-12)
      - Surveys, 1990-09-25–1990-10-09 (Box-folder 110/1)
        Two surveys on peoples' attitudes toward insurance companies.
    - Tony Schwartz public service announcements client list, undated (Box-folder 110/2)
      Compiled lists of clients for whom Tony Schwartz created public service announcements as well as political and commercial campaigns. The lists were compiled for the Library of Congress by Schwartz.
      See also Commercial clients list.
    - The Public Agenda Foundation correspondence and research, 1978-02-06–1978-05-09 (Box-folder 110/3)
    - Public Citizen correspondence and reports, 1994-06-13–1995-05-02 (Box-folder 110/4)
      Intended for voice actors: Alan Bleviss, Michaela Schwartz.
    - Rainforest Alliance research and correspondence, 1986-11-04–1988-07-20 (Box-folder 110/5)
    - Rent Stabilization Association script and report, circa 1983 (Box-folder 110/6)
      Includes an association survey report.
    - R.J. Reynolds family scripts, correspondence, and other material, 1986-10–1987-11-22 (Box-folder 110/7)
      Anti-smoking scripts, correspondence, research materials, and photos.
      See also the Patrick Reynolds Foundation for a Smokefree America and WMCA.
      - Slides of Patrick Reynolds and Reynolds family members, 1987 and undated (Box 203)
        Thirty-eight 35 mm color slides, taken on various dates, of Reynolds family members and related locations, as well as portrait shots of Patrick Reynolds.
    - Robert Wood Johnson Foundation anti-smoking material, 1992–1997
      - Correspondence and research, 1992-08-27–1992-11-16 (Box-folder 110/8)
        See also Center for Media in the Public Interest (CMPI) publication work.
      - Scripts, correspondence, and research, 1992-07-17–1997-08-08 (Box-folder 110/9)
        See also CMPI.
      - Radio surveys, 1994-10-27 (Box-folder 110/10)
    - Roswell Park Cancer Institute anti-smoking scripts and correspondence, 1992-10-09–1992-10-13 (Box-folder 111/1)
      Other sponsors include: Country Health Department and American Cancer Society.
    - Janet Sackman anti-smoking scripts and interview, 1991-11-20–1998-05-08 (Box-folder 111/2)
      Lucky Strike model Janet Sackman suffered throat and lung cancer.
      See also Task Force for Tobacco-Free Women and Girls.
    - SAFE Coalition scripts regarding the Michigan tobacco law, 1994-10-20–1994-10-21 (Box-folder 111/3)
    - Safeblood Foundation of America script, undated (Box-folder 111/4)
    - Shoplifting script, undated (Box-folder 111/5)
    - "Sidewalk to Salvation," Los Angeles Times anti-smoking article, 1993-06-11 (Box-folder 111/6)
    - Sierra Club scripts and contract, 1998-06-24–1998-08-11 (Box-folder 111/7)
    - Smoke Free America interview and correspondence, 1988-07-25 (Box-folder 111/8)
    - Smokefree Educational Services, Inc., 1991–1997
      Also known as Anti-Smoking Educational Services.
      Joe Cherner, president.
      See also First Alert, Patrolmen's Benevolent Association PSA awards, and City University of New York (CUNY) Health.
      - Scripts and reports, 1991-07-17–1994-03-08 (Box-folder 111/9)
      - Promotional materials and correspondence, 1993-01–1993-03-30 (Box-folder 111/10)
      - Scripts and correspondence, 1992-09-24–1997-07-02 (Box-folder 111/11)
    - Smoking Policy Institute correspondence and research, 1988-01-27–1988-08-01 (Box-folder 111/12)
      Correspondence and research materials documenting Tony Schwartz's involvement on the board.
    - Solomon, Relihan, Blake reports, 1993-12-02–1994-02-24 (Box-folder 111/13)
      American Federation of Television and Radio Artists HR reports.
      Provider of legal services, Phoenix, Arizona.
    - Star Foundation scripts, correspondence, and research materials, 1999-04-27–1999-05-05 (Box-folder 111/14)
    - St. John's Hospital anti-smoking scripts, 1986-03-27–1986-04-14 (Box-folder 111/15)
    - Stop Cancer Program anti-smoking script, 1989-01-10–1989-01-11 (Box-folder 111/16)
    - Stop Teenage Addiction to Tobacco correspondence and research, 1979–1988-08 (Box-folder 111/17)
      The organization's acronym is STAT.
    - The Taft Institute script and report, 1994-10-10–1994-10-14 (Box-folder 111/18)
      See also WQXR.
    - Task Force for Tobacco-Free Women and Girls scripts, 1996-12-26–2000-01-05 (Box-folder 111/19)
      Anti-smoking scripts for one-time Lucky Strike model Janet Sackman.
      See also Janet Sackman.
    - Telecom Bill scripts, 1995-08-28 (Box-folder 111/20)
    - Texas Department of Health invoices, script, and report, 1993-08-26–1993-09-03 (Box-folder 111/21)
      Intended for voice actor: Reenah Lurie Schwartz.
    - Laurence Tisch anti-smoking scripts and research materials, 1989-06-15–1989-07-12 (Box-folder 111/22)
    - Tobacco Control Resource Group contract correspondence, 1993-07-15 (Box-folder 111/23)
    - Tobacco Free Coalition of Lancaster County scripts, 1986-03-17–1987-10-28 (Box-folder 111/24)
    - United Bank of Austin scripts, 1985-03-15–1985-07-25 (Box-folder 111/25)
    - United Jewish Appeal correspondence, 1986-04-29 (Box-folder 111/26)
    - U.S. Catholic Conference research material, photographs, and correspondence, 1984-02-03–1984-11-21 (Box-folder 112/1)
    - Voice Foundation scripts, correspondence, and other material, 1979-07–1986-12-16 (Box-folder 112/2)
      Scripts, correspondence, project proposal, photos, and brochures.
    - Voice Foundation slides, circa 1981 (Box 203)
      Nine 35 mm color slides showing normal and damaged larynges.
    - Voting script, 1992-09-30 (Box-folder 112/3)
    - War and Peace Foundation research material, 1988-03-28–1997-10-06 (Box-folder 112/4)
      See also Women's International League for Peace and Freedom.
    - War No More Foundation script, undated (Box-folder 112/5)
    - Windsoki Tapes scripts, 1992-04-27 (Box-folder 112/6)
    - WMCA, 1985–1988
      See also R.J. Reynolds family.
      - Correspondence and research materials, 1986-01-30–1988-05-11 (Box-folder 112/7)
        Includes material on the Patricia McCann Program.
      - Scripts, 1985-09–1986-06-25 (Box-folder 112/8)
    - WNYC radio scripts, correspondence, and research material, 1966-08-12–1994-12-19 (Box-folder 112/9)
      See also New York State Council on the Arts.
      Additionally, see recordings of Schwartz's WNYC radio programs in the Schwartz Collection; WNYC business correspondence; program guide, transcripts, and other publications-related material; and the WNYC subject file.
    - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom correspondence, research materials, and scripts, 1999-12–2000-03-15 (Box-folder 112/10)
      Includes material relating to the Global Resource Action Center for the Environment (GRACE) and the NGO Committee on Disarmament, Inc.
      See also War and Peace Foundation.
  - Client projects: commercial/for-profit work, 1958–2004, undated
    Business materials, arranged by client, for commercial/for-profit radio and television advertisements produced by Tony Schwartz. The clients range from local New York businesses (Bamberger’s Department Store, Kavanagh's Furniture Store, TV Shopper, etc.) to international companies (Apple, CBS, Excedrin, Pepsi-Cola, etc.). The bulk of the material consists of scripts, correspondence, and research materials, such as newspaper clippings, surveys and brochures. Other material includes photographs, posters, storyboards, American Federation of Television and Radio Artists HR reports, receipts and contracts.
    Please note some commercial clients might also be found in other series.
    - The 800 Marketing Group scripts, contracts, correspondence, and work orders, 1997-04-30–1997-10-29 (Box-folder 113/1)
      Radio and television scripts, contracts, correspondence, and work orders for 1-800-ACCIDENT, 1-800-BANKRUPT, and 1-800-LAWYERS radio spots.
      Possibly 1-800-COCAINE.
    - AAUP, Adelphi University scripts, correspondence,and other material, 1985-09-09–1990-12-19 (Box-folder 113/2)
      Includes scripts, correspondence, contracts, research, and an American Federation of Television and Radio Artists HR report.
      Chapter of the American Association of University Professors.
    - AAUP, Rutgers University scripts, correspondence, and report, 1990-08-07–1996-01-31 (Box-folder 113/3)
    - AAUP, University of Rhode Island scripts, correspondence, and research materials, 1984-09-21–1986-12-24 (Box-folder 113/4)
    - Jim S Adler, attorney, scripts, correspondence, and other material, 1994-03-30–1994-05-19 (Box-folder 113/5)
      Also includes research materials and contracts.
    - Aetna Insurance Company scripts, correspondence, and research materials, 1988-04-03–1988-09-01 (Box-folder 113/6)
      Relates to an Aetna study of public attitudes toward the insurance crisis.
    - AHSC (Architecture for Health Science & Commerce) scripts, 1988-05-13–1988-06-24 (Box-folder 113/7)
    - Alexander's scripts, correspondence, and research, 1990-11-18–1991-03-18 (Box-folder 113/8)
    - American Assurance Underwriters Group scripts and correspondence, 1987-08-07–1987-11-09 (Box-folder 113/9)
    - America's Industrial Heritage Project correspondence, 1992-08-14–1992-08-19 (Box-folder 113/10)
    - American Security Systems scripts, 1983-02-07–1983-11-22 (Box-folder 113/11)
    - Amsterdam News scripts, contract, and research materials, 1988-12-01–1989-07-24 (Box-folder 114/1)
      Intended voice actor: Bill Tatum.
    - Apple Computer, 1989–1992
      - Scripts, 1989-07-28–1989-11-28 (Box-folder 114/2, 7)
      - Research materials, 1992-07-08–1992-07-14 (Box-folder 114/3)
      - "Love letters from people who are changing the world" report, 1989 (Box-folder 114/4)
        Fan letters from Apple clients.
      - Business correspondence, 1989-06-12–1989-10 (Box-folder 114/5)
        Contracts and letters.
      - Interviews, 1989-01-12–1989-11 (Box-folder 114/6)
      - Scripts, 1989-07-26–1992-07-17 (Box-folder 114/2, 7)
    - Archer/Malmo advertising agency, 1996-03-04–1997-03-13 (Box-folder 114/8)
    - Asia Society research, interview, and correspondence, 1981-03-06–1986-07-31 (Box-folder 114/9)
      Includes an interview with Chinese-American composer Chou Wen-chung.
    - Associated Builders and Owners of New York correspondence, 1983-04-29–1983-05-03 (Box-folder 115/1)
    - AT&T, 1985–1995
      See also Landco Labs, Inc. receipts.
      - Articles and correspondence, 1995-08-14–1995-11-03 (Box-folder 115/2)
      - Scripts and correspondence, 1985-10-29–1986-02-14 (Box-folder 115/3)
        Includes original artwork of puppet master dangling various media.
      - Scripts and contracts, 1991-01-23–1991-09-09 (Box-folder 115/4)
      - Research, 1990-12-31–1991-02-21 (Box-folder 115/5)
      - Language line scripts, research, and correspondence, 1990–1992 (Box-folder 115/6-7)
    - B Smith's Restaurant scripts and research materials, 1987-02-05–197-06-15 (Box-folder 115/8)
    - Bamberger's Department Store, 1976–1984
      - Sunday shopping, 1980-10-03 (Box-folder 115/9)
      - Scripts, 1982-11-30–1983-09-23 (Box-folder 115/10-11)
      - Scripts, 1982-01-11–1982-11-29 (Box-folder 116/1-2)
      - Scripts, 1984 (Box-folder 116/3-5)
      - Scripts, 1983-10-10–1984-02-11 (Box-folder 116/6)
      - Scripts, 1976-10-25–1979-03-08 (Box-folder 116/7-9)
        Scripts in order by date recorded.
        Includes materials for an anti-shoplifting campaign.
      - Scripts, 1980-01-01–1981-12-28 (Box-folder 117/1-3)
    - Bayer aspirin scripts, undated (Box-folder 117/4)
      Two scripts for extra strength aspirin.
    - Baystate Medical Center correspondence and scripts, 1986-07-01 (Box-folder 117/5)
    - Beep Masters scripts for various television commercials, 1959-11-02–1961-01-06, undated (Box-folder 117/6)
      Clients/products include: General Electric, Post Sugar Crisp cereal (with story board), Vic Tanny Silver Anniversary, Bazooka Bubble Gum, Manager Hotels Coffee, Old Gold Spin Filters, Jell-O, La Rosa Spaghetti, and Procter & Gamble. Most scripts are undated. Grey Advertising, Inc. appears to have been involved with most of the projects.
      It is not known what Beep Masters signifies in the context of Tony Schwartz's work. It is possible that beeps were signified by the red pencil dots after each line of dialog in the script. They could have been markers used for editing purposes in audio or film.
    - Bell Telephone correspondence, 1990-07-19–1990-12-28 (Box-folder 117/7)
    - Beth Israel Medical Center scripts, contracts, and research materials, 1992-01–1993-03-02 (Box-folder 117/8)
    - Alan Bleviss, voice actor, scripts, 1988-12-29–1998-08-06 (Box-folder 117/9)
      Advertising scripts intended for voice actor Alan Bleviss, who frequently worked with Tony Schwartz. Included are scripts representing the following clients: Greenmarkets, League of Voluntary Hospitals, Emergency Medical Services, Competitive Long Distance Coalition, Friends of Ruth Messinger, TAFT, WQXR, Bredesen for Governor, Bose, ULTRALIFE, 1010 WINS, Patrolmen's Benevolent Association, Journey of the Heart, Cricket, Senator Jay Rockefeller, Public Citizen, West Virginia Citizen Action Group, Society of Orthopedic Surgeons, Inc., New York City Fire Department, Solomon Relihan & Blake, Green '93, New York Power Authority, Alliance for Quality Education, Naumburg Bandshell, Organ Donor Awareness, New York City Police Foundation, Handgun Control, AT&T, Crimestoppers, Rutgers AAUP, Kavanagh, Families Concerned About AIDS, Military Families Support Network, Congregation B'nai Jeshurun, Adelphi AAUP, Coalition for Zoning Law Enforcement, and Department of Investigation.
      There is one 8x10 inch photograph of Tony Schwartz and Alan Bleviss recording together, signed by Alan Bleviss.
    - Blue Cross & Blue Shield, 1985–1986
      - Access America scripts and correspondence, 1985-08-31–1986-02-13 (Box-folder 117/10)
        Access America is also Blue Cross Blue Shield.
      - Empire Blue Cross & Blue Shield scripts and correspondence, 1985-08-12–1986-01-14 (Box-folder 117/11)
        Includes Greater New York Safety Council public service announcements.
        Brouillard Communications.
      - Spanish spot scripts, 1985-08-19–1985-09-23 (Box-folder 117/12)
    - Boardroom Reports, 1987–1992
      See also Landco Labs, Inc. receipts, "How to Use Radio Advertising Most Effectively," and "Puncturing Advertising Myths."
      - I-Power scripts, correspondence, and research materials, 1991-11-18–1992-06-24 (Box-folder 117/13)
      - Scripts and research materials, 1987-07-20–1991-02-25 (Box-folder 117/14)
        Intended for: Bob Landers voice actor.
    - Bottom line scripts, correspondence, ad mats, and research materials, 1990-09-26–1991-06-14 (Box-folder 118/1-2)
      See also New York City Police Foundation.
    - Bristol Myers correspondence, 1976-03-13–1991-10-03 (Box-folder 118/3)
      Regarding a breast cancer project and an oil industry project.
    - Business Week, 1973–1985
      - Scripts and research materials, 1973-07–1985-10-21 (Box-folder 118/4)
        Magazine and scripts. Two reports titled "Report on a Cassette Program for Business Week" and "Continuing Report on Audio-cassettes for Business Week."
        "Trout and Ries" written on original folder.
      - Research materials, 1973-04 (Box-folder 118/5)
        One report titled "A Study of Advertising Decision-makers."
    - Cablevision, 1993–1994
      - Scripts, 1993-07-02–1993-10-01 (Box-folder 118/6)
      - Contracts, correspondence, and research materials, 1993-04–1994-01-21 (Box-folder 118/7)
        Includes an American Federation of Television and Radio Artists HR report and three photographs of antennas.
    - Café 43 scripts and correspondence, 1988-05-11 (Box-folder 118/8)
    - CBS Radio, 1974–1992
      - Scripts and contracts, 1991-09–1992-12-07 (Box-folder 118/9)
      - Research and correspondence, 1974-04-03–1993-07-19 (Box-folder 118/10)
    - CBS Television Network script, 1959-08 (Box-folder 119/1)
      "Through a Glass, Darkly" script from the religious program Lamp Unto My Feet.
      Tony Schwartz was documentary recordist.
    - Center for Science in the Public Interest correspondence and scripts, 1985-03-22–1991-01-02 (Box-folder 119/2)
      Includes Martin Himmel Health scripts.
    - Clicquot Champagne scripts, correspondence, and research, 1988-06–1996-10-04 (Box-folder 119/3)
      Intended for voice actor: Mireille Guiliano.
    - Coliseum Books, 1990–2001
      - Correspondence, 1994-11-26–2001-04-09 (Box-folder 119/4)
      - Scripts, 1990-12-03–1996-12-23 (Box-folder 119/5)
        Intended for voice actor: Bob Sevra.
    - Tony Schwartz client list, undated (Box-folder 119/6)
      Compiled lists of Tony Schwartz's commercial clients. It is unknown who compiled the older lists, but Tony Schwartz compiled the newer list for the Library of Congress. One list each of political, public service, and commercial clients.
      See also PSA client list.
    - Committee for National Health Insurance material, 1989–1990-08-22 (Box-folder 119/7)
    - Committee Opposed to State-Tech scripts and research, 1974-09-18–1976-12-01 (Box-folder 119/8)
    - Compoz correspondence and scripts, 1986-05-15–1986-12-16 (Box-folder 119/9)
      See also Bantron in Schwartz's PSA clients.
    - Cooper Square Bookstore scripts, 1990-04-13–1990-04-14 (Box-folder 119/10)
    - Cosmosol material, 1991-03-27–1991-11-25 (Box-folder 119/11)
    - Cricket scripts, correspondence, and research materials, 1994-06-16–1994-06-28 (Box-folder 119/12)
    - Critical Intelligence scripts, correspondence, and research, 1994-06-09–1994-07-20 (Box-folder 120/1)
    - Cultural Institutions Group contracts and correspondence, 1992-01-01–1992-06-30 (Box-folder 120/2)
    - CUNY (City University of New York) scripts and research materials, 1990-03-15–1993-05-08 (Box-folder 120/3)
      See also Concerned Friends of Physical Education, First Alert, SmokeFree Educational Services, and Patrolmen's Benevolent Association scripts.
    - C.W. Post Center, Long Island University, 1979-12-17–1981-08-04 (Box-folder 120/4)
    - Slides of the C.W. Post Center, Long Island University, 1980–1981 and undated (Box 203)
      Five 35 mm color slides of C.W. Post buildings.
    - New York Daily News, 1978–1990
      - Scripts, correspondence and research materials, 1990-01-24–1990-12-13 (Box-folder 120/5-6)
        Includes contracts and an American Federation of TV and Radio Artists HR report.